WALTER CLAYTON



+32476013223 walter.h.clayton@gmail.com



"DON'T MAKE ME THINK"

PROFILE

Web developer with a passion for making products intuitive and beautiful. Able to translate abstract ideas into visual web components. Developed a somatotype web app, a nation-ranking ecommerce website, contributed to the improvement of European Agencies and Associations CMS platforms, and designed family offices asset management website and app. Translating solutions into code and working across many different APIs, third-party integrations, and databases. Always keeps up to date with the latest technologies and innovations. Experienced team leader, player, and independent worker, who likes to achieve and deliver. Enjoys working with people who ask strong questions, have visual taste and logic, a clear vision, an entrepreneurial mindset, and communicate short, sweet, and concisely.

SKILLS

Excellent in the frontend, making visually attractive designs, interactive, responsive, and user friendly.

Sufficiency in the backend, good understanding of project structure, MVC, ORM, and database design.

Competent with version control systems and basic know-how of testing, deployment and hosting.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Frontend: Javascript, Typescript, React, Vue.js, Wordpress, Bootstrap5, MUI, Axios, Three.js, CSS3, Affinity Publisher, Figma, Flourish

Backend: Node.js, MongoDB, MySQL

Devops: Heroku, Godaddy, Render, WPengine

Operating Systems: Mac

Other: Remote working, VS Code, Git, Github, Jira, Agile Methodology, GDPR, integration testing

(Postman)

EXPERIENCE

Freelance Frontend Developer, Brussels, Belgium — August 2021 - Present

www.afitpilot.com

Key responsibilities for the website:

- Author, and content creator
- Designed and implemented mockups, visual assets, pages, and avatars (using Figma, Typescript, React, MUI, Affinity Publisher)
- Wrote full devops and contributions documentation for developers
- Managed a team of 3 developers (2 frontend and 1 backend), Agile Methodology

Key achievement for the website:

- Finished the MVP in 2 months

www.leagueofnations.co.uk

Key responsibilities for the website:

- Designed and created algorithm and website (Wordpress, Figma, Excel)
- Wrote full documentation for adding data to the algorithm and posting content on the website.
- Designing and implementing full UX click funnel for conversions (social media, landing page, freebie, paid content).
- Managed an intern web developer, Agile Methodology

Key achievement for the website:

- Fully Functional

Solution Analyst, NTT DATA, Brussels, Belgium — September 2021 - September 2022

Key responsibilities:

- Conducting functional workshops
- Working in close collaboration with Drupal Developers, UX/UI designers, Communication experts and key stakeholders to deliver the functional requirements.
- Writing functional analysis documents
- Designing Use Case Graphs

Key projects:

- Projects included migrating the European Research Council (ERC), the European Securities and Markets Authority (ESMA), and the European Banking Authority (EBA) from old Drupal to new Drupal versions, and gathering the requirements for creating the European Cybersecurity Collaboration Platform.

$\label{lem:lemma:com} \textbf{Lead Frontend Developer, Finlight, London-April 2020 - Present www.finlight.com}$

Key responsibilities for the website:

- Completed full redesign of existing website to improve navigation, enhance visuals and strengthen search engine rankings.
- Collaborated with marketing department to determine organisational need and design pages to meet goals.
- Conducted testing and review of website design for responsiveness, clarity and effectiveness.
- Converted graphic designs to usable web images using Adobe Photo Shop.

Key responsibilities for the web app:

- Designed intuitive graphical user interfaces to improve UX onboarding.

- Creating SPAs with Vuejs.

Key achievements:

- 2 Step Authentication with Firebase
- Onboarding tour for new users with Vuejs router.
- SEO, accessibility, best practices and performance above 90%

Web Developer, BeCode, Brussels — June 2019 - April 2020

Key responsibilities:

- Developed prototype full-stack web applications which processed, analysed, and rendered data visually.

Web Developer, TechMex, London — January 2019 - June 2019

Key responsibilities:

- Studied basic project requirements with technical lead and planned development strategies.
- Developed user interfaces with Javascript frameworks, HTML5 and CSS3.

LANGUAGES

French: Fluent English: Fluent

Dutch: B1 level (limited working proficiency) **Spanish:** A2 level (aiming to speak fluently)

EDUCATION

Udemy — Completed many courses such as Web Developer Bootcamp, Business Analyst, Business Models, Project Management, 2019-2023

BeCode — Web Developer Bootcamp, 2019-2020

OpenClassroom — Completed courses on UI/UX Design and Lean Start-up, 2019

University of Brighton — First Class Honours Bsc(Hons) Sport and Exercise Science, 2014-2017

LEISURE AND RECENT ACTIVITIES

Hackathons: IBM and Telenet Hackathon.

Reading: Product-Led-Growth - How to Build a Product That Sells Itself, by Bush Wes

Podcast: Listen weekly to TechTent podcasts.

Entertainment: Salsa, CrossFit

Full Driving Licence: B